<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/</link><description>Recent content on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New publication in Bio-based and Applied Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-10-bio-based-and-applied-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-10-bio-based-and-applied-economics/</guid><description>This paper explores the potential usefulness and possible pitfalls of using integrated choice and latent variable models (hybrid choice models) on stated choice data to inform policy. Using a series of Monte-Carlo simulations, we consider how model selection depends on the strength of relationship between the latent variable and preferences and the strength of relationship between the latent variable and the indicator. Our findings show that integrated choice and latent variable models are difficult to estimate, even when the data generating process is known.</description></item><item><title>New publication in PLoS ONE</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-09-plos-one/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-09-plos-one/</guid><description>We report and interpret preferences of a sample of the Dutch adult population for different strategies to end the so-called ‘intelligent lockdown’ which their government had put in place in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Using a discrete choice experiment, we invited participants to make a series of choices between policy scenarios aimed at relaxing the lockdown, which were specified not in terms of their nature (e.g. whether or not to allow schools to re-open) but in terms of their effects along seven dimensions.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Environmental and Resource Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-08-environmental-and-resource-economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-08-environmental-and-resource-economics/</guid><description>The growth in global aquaculture production may address the lack of sustainability in wild fisheries, alleviate poverty in rural and coastal areas, and help meet the worldwide increase in demand for animal protein. However, there is an ongoing debate about the severity of the environmental impact of aquaculture production. Investing in new high-tech production systems can address both productivity growth and the environmental externalities, but high investment costs hinder adoption of high-tech production methods.</description></item><item><title>Outstanding Paper Award in European Review of Agricultural Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-07-outstanding-paper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-07-outstanding-paper/</guid><description>I am thrilled to have received the Outstanding Paper Award 2019 in the European Review of Agricultural Economics together with Danny Campbell for our paper &amp;ldquo;Accommodating statisficing behavior in stated choice experiments&amp;rdquo;. The paper is freely available from the link at the bottom.
Reference:
Sandorf, E.D. &amp;amp; Campbell, D., 2019, Accommodating satisficing behavior in stated choice experiments, European Review of Agricultural Economics, 46:1, 133-162</description></item><item><title>New publication in Resource and Energy Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-05-resource-and-energy-economics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2020/2020-05-resource-and-energy-economics/</guid><description>Internet panels are increasingly used for stated preference research. Because members of such panels receive compensation for each completed survey, one concern is that over time this creates professional respondents who answer surveys solely for the monetary compensation. We identify professional respondents using data on panel tenure, survey response frequency, completion rate and total number of completed surveys. We find evidence of two types of professional respondents: “hyperactives” who answer surveys frequently and “experienced” who have long panel tenure and a large number of completed surveys.</description></item><item><title>Persistent storage on Shinyapps.io: Storing your survey responses responsibly</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-03-persistent-storage-in-shiny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-03-persistent-storage-in-shiny/</guid><description>In this post, I will outline how I set up persistent storage and transfer of data from a Shiny survey to a MariaDB using SSL certificates. How I set up the survey and how I handled URL redirects in and out of the survey are topics for future posts. Coming up with a satisfactory solution to this problem took a lot of trial and error (and Googleing&amp;hellip;). It turned out that all of the challenges related to persistent storage, sending data to a database, preventing SQL injection attacks and securing the data traffic with SSL certificates had existing solutions.</description></item><item><title>The Pursuit of Fellowship to the Higher Education Academy</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-02-associate-fellow-of-hea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-02-associate-fellow-of-hea/</guid><description>As an early career academic with ambitions of a career in academia, I spend much of my time and energy on doing research and writing papers. This is what we are judged on. This is what matters. Or is it?
When I entered academia as an undergraduate student, I did not find many of my teachers and lectures impressive. The classes were large and mostly consisted of covering the material on the blackboard, overhead (yeah - some still used that in the mid 00s) or PowerPoint.</description></item><item><title>jekyll-pro-theme: A jekyll theme to use with Github Pages</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-01-jekyll-pro-theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-01-jekyll-pro-theme/</guid><description>As part of the INSPiRE project I have had to create and host a project website (a work in progress by any definition) and create and host an online survey. With no background in web design and only a vague idea of HTML, CSS and JavaScript, I got going. My first attempts was with Google Sites, but I have to admit, I found working with the templates a bit clunky. I was not happy with the way the website ended up looking.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Conservation Biology</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2019/2019-08-conservation-biology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2019/2019-08-conservation-biology/</guid><description>There is increasing pressure to use currently untapped resources in the deep sea, raising questions regarding ecosystem service trade‐offs in these often unknown areas. We assessed the trade‐offs between protection of cold‐water coral reefs and economic activities, such as fisheries and petroleum extraction, through a survey of a representative sample of the populations of Norway and Ireland. Choice‐experiment surveys were conducted in workshop settings and through the internet. Both survey approaches provided some similar results, such as preferences for protection.</description></item><item><title>obfuscatoR: Obfuscation Game Designs is now available on CRAN</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-08-obfuscator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-08-obfuscator/</guid><description>Chorus et al. (2019) put forward the hypothesis that sometimes when people make choices they wish to hide their true motivation from a potential onlooker. The obfuscatoR package allows users to easily create obfuscation experiments to test the obfuscation hypothesis, i.e. when properly incentivized - are people able to obfuscate? The package has an easy to use interface and includes several options for the user to adjust the difficulty of the experiment for both the decision maker and observer.</description></item><item><title>Poster presented at LEEPin2019 in Exeter</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-06-leepin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-06-leepin/</guid><description>I gave a poster presentation titled: &amp;ldquo;The effect of device experience and time of day on stated preferences&amp;rdquo; at the LEEPin2019 Conference on 24th - 26th of June 2019 at the University of Exeter. The working paper, on which the poster is based, is concerned with the response quality of people answering stated preference surveys on their mobile phones compared to a desktop computer. We use the number of surveys a given respondent has answered on each device as a proxy for experience answering surveys on a particular device.</description></item><item><title>Seminar with HERU in Aberdeen</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-05-heru/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-05-heru/</guid><description>I was invited to give a seminar in the Health Economics Research Group (HERU) seminar series in Aberdeen on the 31st of May 2019. The title of the talk was: &amp;ldquo;The search for something better - A consideration set model&amp;rdquo;. The role that information search plays in economic decision making has long been recognized. The seminar focused on how the search for new information about alternatives plays an important part in how consideration sets are formed, i.</description></item><item><title>The purpose of the blog</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2019/2019-04-the-purpose-of-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2019/2019-04-the-purpose-of-the-blog/</guid><description>With the new and revamped website, I have decided to start a blog. I am not a very experienced blogger and was introduced to the concept of having one through the INSPiRE project. To me, the blog will be a pathway to impact. A place where I can provide a more personal opinion on the research that I, and my colleagues, do. Much of the work that I do focuses on the use of advanded choice models to understand better how people make decisions in markets (both real and hypothetical).</description></item><item><title>New position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</guid><description>Today I started my new position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling. The position is for 2 years and is part of the INSPiRE Project. The project is funded by the European Research Council under the Horizon 2020 - Marie Sklodowska-Curie Individaul Fellowship program. The project is in collaboration with Professor Danny Campbell. I have worked extensively with Professor Campbell in the past, and I am exited to continue that work now in Stirling.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Environmental and Resource Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-10-environmental-and-resource-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-10-environmental-and-resource-economics/</guid><description>Stated preference practitioners are increasingly relying on internet panels to gather data, but emerging evidence suggests potential limitations with respect to respondent and response quality in such panels. We identify groups of inattentive respondents who have failed to watch information videos provided in the survey to completion. Our results show that inattentive respondents have a higher cost sensitivity, are more likely to have a small scale parameter, and are more likely to ignore the non-cost attributes.</description></item><item><title>Paper presented at the World Congress for Environmental and Resource Economists</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-07-wcere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-07-wcere/</guid><description>I presented the working paper &amp;ldquo;Assessing the impact of &amp;lsquo;professional&amp;rsquo; respondents using an integrated choice and latent variable model&amp;rdquo; at the 6th World Congress for Environmental and Resource Economists in Gothenburg. The paper addresses a concern among stated preference practioners relying on online panels to gather data, that some panel members may have substantial experience with answering surveys and that they are &amp;ldquo;in it for the money&amp;rdquo;. While not inherently bad or irrational, if these respondents are motivated only by the monetary compensation, and engage in simplifying survey behavior to obtain the compensation with the least amount of effort, then this may lead to poorer data quality.</description></item><item><title>New publication in European Review of Agricultural Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-07-european-review-of-agricultural-economics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-07-european-review-of-agricultural-economics/</guid><description>Accumulating evidence suggests that respondents in stated choice experiments use simplifying strategies. Such behaviour is a deviation from random utility theory and can lead to wrong inferences regarding preferences. This is a first attempt to systematically explore satisficing in stated choice experiments. We consider 944 satisficing rules and allow respondents to revise the rules adopted throughout the choice sequence. Only a minority of respondents used the same satisficing rule across the entire sequence.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Energy Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-05-energy-economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-05-energy-economics/</guid><description>In this paper, we report on a discrete choice experiment aimed at eliciting Swedish households’ willingness-to-accept a compensation for restrictions on household electricity and heating use during peak hours. When analyzing data from discrete choice experiments it is typically assumed that people make rational utility maximizing decisions, i.e., that they consider all of the attribute information and compare all alternatives. However, mounting evidence shows that people use a wide range of simplifying strategies that are inconsistent with utility maximization.</description></item><item><title>Taught Discrete Choice Analysis in R in Karlsruhe</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</guid><description>I taught the course Discrete Choice Analysis with R for researchers at the Europäisches Institut für Energieforschnung (EIfER) EDF-KIT from the 8th - 12th of October 2018. The three day course covered introduction to stated preference experimental design and analysis of discrete choice data. Each day started with 3 hours of lectures in the morning followed by 3 hours of hands-on work after lunch.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Journal of Choice Modeling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-02-journal-of-choice-modeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-02-journal-of-choice-modeling/</guid><description>When analyzing discrete choice data we assume that respondents compare alternatives and make a utility maximizing choice. The majority of DCEs use a matrix display with one row per attribute and one column per alternative. A comparison by alternatives implies that respondents process the choice task column-by-column. However, evidence from psychology and judgment and decision making research suggest that learned reading patterns dominate and as such the standard matrix display might induce processing by attributes rather than alternatives.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Ocean and Coastal Management</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2017/2017-05-ocean-and-coastal-management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2017/2017-05-ocean-and-coastal-management/</guid><description>It is well-known that operating within the boundaries of a national park provides commercial actors with the opportunity to charge a price premium, though this has to a lesser degree been demonstrated for marine protected areas. We estimate national tourists' willingness-to-pay a price premium for boat trips in the Nha Trang Bay Marine Protected Are, Vietnam, using a discrete choice experiment. Our results show that tourists are willing to pay an average price premium of 18 USD per trip for a large improvement in environmental quality, and that avoiding the loss of jobs for local fishermen is of minor importance.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Journal of Choice Modeling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-09-journal-of-choice-modeling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-09-journal-of-choice-modeling/</guid><description>We seek to disentangle the effect of knowledge about an environmental good on respondents' propensity to ignore one or more attributes on the choice cards in a discrete choice experiment eliciting people&amp;rsquo;s preferences for increased protection of cold-water corals in Norway. We hypothesize that a respondent&amp;rsquo;s level of knowledge influences the degree to which she ignores attributes. Respondents participated in a quiz on cold-water coral prior to the valuation task and we use the result of the quiz as an ex-ante measure of their knowledge.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Ecological Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-06-ecological-economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-06-ecological-economics/</guid><description>We compare two discrete choice experiments eliciting willingness-to-pay (WTP) for increased cold-water coral protection in Norway using valuation workshops and an internet panel survey with videos. The video presentation provides the same visual presentation of information about the good and valuation task as in the valuation workshop. In doing so, we are the first to compare these survey modes. The two survey modes perform equally well with respect to sampling, but the internet survey gives significantly lower WTP estimates.</description></item></channel></rss>