<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/</link><description>Recent content in 2020 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Outstanding Paper Award in European Review of Agricultural Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-07-outstanding-paper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-07-outstanding-paper/</guid><description>I am thrilled to have received the Outstanding Paper Award 2019 in the European Review of Agricultural Economics together with Danny Campbell for our paper &amp;ldquo;Accommodating statisficing behavior in stated choice experiments&amp;rdquo;. The paper is freely available from the link at the bottom.
Reference:
Sandorf, E.D. &amp;amp; Campbell, D., 2019, Accommodating satisficing behavior in stated choice experiments, European Review of Agricultural Economics, 46:1, 133-162</description></item><item><title>jekyll-pro-theme: A jekyll theme to use with Github Pages</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-01-jekyll-pro-theme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2020/2020-01-jekyll-pro-theme/</guid><description>As part of the INSPiRE project I have had to create and host a project website (a work in progress by any definition) and create and host an online survey. With no background in web design and only a vague idea of HTML, CSS and JavaScript, I got going. My first attempts was with Google Sites, but I have to admit, I found working with the templates a bit clunky. I was not happy with the way the website ended up looking.</description></item></channel></rss>