<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New publication in Environmental and Resource Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-10-environmental-and-resource-economics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-10-environmental-and-resource-economics/</guid><description>Stated preference practitioners are increasingly relying on internet panels to gather data, but emerging evidence suggests potential limitations with respect to respondent and response quality in such panels. We identify groups of inattentive respondents who have failed to watch information videos provided in the survey to completion. Our results show that inattentive respondents have a higher cost sensitivity, are more likely to have a small scale parameter, and are more likely to ignore the non-cost attributes.</description></item><item><title>New publication in European Review of Agricultural Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-07-european-review-of-agricultural-economics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-07-european-review-of-agricultural-economics/</guid><description>Accumulating evidence suggests that respondents in stated choice experiments use simplifying strategies. Such behaviour is a deviation from random utility theory and can lead to wrong inferences regarding preferences. This is a first attempt to systematically explore satisficing in stated choice experiments. We consider 944 satisficing rules and allow respondents to revise the rules adopted throughout the choice sequence. Only a minority of respondents used the same satisficing rule across the entire sequence.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Energy Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-05-energy-economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-05-energy-economics/</guid><description>In this paper, we report on a discrete choice experiment aimed at eliciting Swedish households’ willingness-to-accept a compensation for restrictions on household electricity and heating use during peak hours. When analyzing data from discrete choice experiments it is typically assumed that people make rational utility maximizing decisions, i.e., that they consider all of the attribute information and compare all alternatives. However, mounting evidence shows that people use a wide range of simplifying strategies that are inconsistent with utility maximization.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Journal of Choice Modeling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-02-journal-of-choice-modeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2018/2018-02-journal-of-choice-modeling/</guid><description>When analyzing discrete choice data we assume that respondents compare alternatives and make a utility maximizing choice. The majority of DCEs use a matrix display with one row per attribute and one column per alternative. A comparison by alternatives implies that respondents process the choice task column-by-column. However, evidence from psychology and judgment and decision making research suggest that learned reading patterns dominate and as such the standard matrix display might induce processing by attributes rather than alternatives.</description></item></channel></rss>