<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/</link><description>Recent content in 2020 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Persistent storage on Shinyapps.io: Storing your survey responses responsibly</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-03-persistent-storage-in-shiny/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-03-persistent-storage-in-shiny/</guid><description>In this post, I will outline how I set up persistent storage and transfer of data from a Shiny survey to a MariaDB using SSL certificates. How I set up the survey and how I handled URL redirects in and out of the survey are topics for future posts. Coming up with a satisfactory solution to this problem took a lot of trial and error (and Googleing&amp;hellip;). It turned out that all of the challenges related to persistent storage, sending data to a database, preventing SQL injection attacks and securing the data traffic with SSL certificates had existing solutions.</description></item><item><title>The Pursuit of Fellowship to the Higher Education Academy</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-02-associate-fellow-of-hea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/blog/2020/2020-02-associate-fellow-of-hea/</guid><description>As an early career academic with ambitions of a career in academia, I spend much of my time and energy on doing research and writing papers. This is what we are judged on. This is what matters. Or is it?
When I entered academia as an undergraduate student, I did not find many of my teachers and lectures impressive. The classes were large and mostly consisted of covering the material on the blackboard, overhead (yeah - some still used that in the mid 00s) or PowerPoint.</description></item></channel></rss>