<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>obfuscatoR: Obfuscation Game Designs is now available on CRAN</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-08-obfuscator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-08-obfuscator/</guid><description>Chorus et al. (2019) put forward the hypothesis that sometimes when people make choices they wish to hide their true motivation from a potential onlooker. The obfuscatoR package allows users to easily create obfuscation experiments to test the obfuscation hypothesis, i.e. when properly incentivized - are people able to obfuscate? The package has an easy to use interface and includes several options for the user to adjust the difficulty of the experiment for both the decision maker and observer.</description></item><item><title>Poster presented at LEEPin2019 in Exeter</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-06-leepin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-06-leepin/</guid><description>I gave a poster presentation titled: &amp;ldquo;The effect of device experience and time of day on stated preferences&amp;rdquo; at the LEEPin2019 Conference on 24th - 26th of June 2019 at the University of Exeter. The working paper, on which the poster is based, is concerned with the response quality of people answering stated preference surveys on their mobile phones compared to a desktop computer. We use the number of surveys a given respondent has answered on each device as a proxy for experience answering surveys on a particular device.</description></item><item><title>Seminar with HERU in Aberdeen</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-05-heru/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2019/2019-05-heru/</guid><description>I was invited to give a seminar in the Health Economics Research Group (HERU) seminar series in Aberdeen on the 31st of May 2019. The title of the talk was: &amp;ldquo;The search for something better - A consideration set model&amp;rdquo;. The role that information search plays in economic decision making has long been recognized. The seminar focused on how the search for new information about alternatives plays an important part in how consideration sets are formed, i.</description></item></channel></rss>