<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Presentation at ENVECHO in Verona</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-09-envecho/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-09-envecho/</guid><description>I gave a presentation at the Environmental Choice workshop in Verona, Italy. This post is copied with permission from ACRG.
Abstract When we analyze how people make choices, we assume taht they are rational utility maximizers. This assumption implies that people have full knowledge of their preferences, complete information about all available alternatives and an infinite ability to make trade-offs between them. These basic assumptions of economics allow us to make consistent predictions and derive welafare estimates.</description></item><item><title>Poster presented at LEEPin2019 in Exeter</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-06-leepin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-06-leepin/</guid><description>I gave a poster presentation titled: &amp;ldquo;The effect of device experience and time of day on stated preferences&amp;rdquo; at the LEEPin2019 Conference on 24th - 26th of June 2019 at the University of Exeter. The working paper, on which the poster is based, is concerned with the response quality of people answering stated preference surveys on their mobile phones compared to a desktop computer. We use the number of surveys a given respondent has answered on each device as a proxy for experience answering surveys on a particular device.</description></item><item><title>Presentation at ICMC2019 in Kobe</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-08-icmc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-08-icmc/</guid><description>I gave a presentation at the International Choice Modeling Conference (ICMC) in Kobe. The title of the presentation was &amp;ldquo;An information search approach to discrete choice analysis&amp;rdquo;. This post is copied with permission from ACRG.
Abstract As choice modelers we observe decision makers’ choices among competing alternatives, and we try to come up with a model that best describes the observed choice behavior. The economic model of the rational utility maximizer is still pervasive.</description></item><item><title>Seminar with HERU in Aberdeen</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-05-heru/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/presentations/2019/2019-05-heru/</guid><description>I was invited to give a seminar in the Health Economics Research Group (HERU) seminar series in Aberdeen on the 31st of May 2019. The title of the talk was: &amp;ldquo;The search for something better - A consideration set model&amp;rdquo;. The role that information search plays in economic decision making has long been recognized. The seminar focused on how the search for new information about alternatives plays an important part in how consideration sets are formed, i.</description></item></channel></rss>