<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2016 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/</link><description>Recent content in 2016 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New publication in Journal of Choice Modeling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-09-journal-of-choice-modeling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-09-journal-of-choice-modeling/</guid><description>We seek to disentangle the effect of knowledge about an environmental good on respondents' propensity to ignore one or more attributes on the choice cards in a discrete choice experiment eliciting people&amp;rsquo;s preferences for increased protection of cold-water corals in Norway. We hypothesize that a respondent&amp;rsquo;s level of knowledge influences the degree to which she ignores attributes. Respondents participated in a quiz on cold-water coral prior to the valuation task and we use the result of the quiz as an ex-ante measure of their knowledge.</description></item><item><title>New publication in Ecological Economics</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-06-ecological-economics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/publications/2016/2016-06-ecological-economics/</guid><description>We compare two discrete choice experiments eliciting willingness-to-pay (WTP) for increased cold-water coral protection in Norway using valuation workshops and an internet panel survey with videos. The video presentation provides the same visual presentation of information about the good and valuation task as in the valuation workshop. In doing so, we are the first to compare these survey modes. The two survey modes perform equally well with respect to sampling, but the internet survey gives significantly lower WTP estimates.</description></item></channel></rss>