<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</guid><description>Today I started my new position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling. The position is for 2 years and is part of the INSPiRE Project. The project is funded by the European Research Council under the Horizon 2020 - Marie Sklodowska-Curie Individaul Fellowship program. The project is in collaboration with Professor Danny Campbell. I have worked extensively with Professor Campbell in the past, and I am exited to continue that work now in Stirling.</description></item><item><title>Taught Discrete Choice Analysis in R in Karlsruhe</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</guid><description>I taught the course Discrete Choice Analysis with R for researchers at the Europäisches Institut für Energieforschnung (EIfER) EDF-KIT from the 8th - 12th of October 2018. The three day course covered introduction to stated preference experimental design and analysis of discrete choice data. Each day started with 3 hours of lectures in the morning followed by 3 hours of hands-on work after lunch.</description></item></channel></rss>