<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 on Erlend Dancke Sandorf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-11-ustir/</guid><description>Today I started my new position as a Marie Sklodowska-Curie Research Fellow with the University of Stirling. The position is for 2 years and is part of the INSPiRE Project. The project is funded by the European Research Council under the Horizon 2020 - Marie Sklodowska-Curie Individaul Fellowship program. The project is in collaboration with Professor Danny Campbell. I have worked extensively with Professor Campbell in the past, and I am exited to continue that work now in Stirling.</description></item><item><title>Paper presented at the World Congress for Environmental and Resource Economists</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-07-wcere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-07-wcere/</guid><description>I presented the working paper &amp;ldquo;Assessing the impact of &amp;lsquo;professional&amp;rsquo; respondents using an integrated choice and latent variable model&amp;rdquo; at the 6th World Congress for Environmental and Resource Economists in Gothenburg. The paper addresses a concern among stated preference practioners relying on online panels to gather data, that some panel members may have substantial experience with answering surveys and that they are &amp;ldquo;in it for the money&amp;rdquo;. While not inherently bad or irrational, if these respondents are motivated only by the monetary compensation, and engage in simplifying survey behavior to obtain the compensation with the least amount of effort, then this may lead to poorer data quality.</description></item><item><title>Taught Discrete Choice Analysis in R in Karlsruhe</title><link>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://edsandorf.me/posts/news/2018/2018-04-karlsruhe/</guid><description>I taught the course Discrete Choice Analysis with R for researchers at the Europäisches Institut für Energieforschnung (EIfER) EDF-KIT from the 8th - 12th of October 2018. The three day course covered introduction to stated preference experimental design and analysis of discrete choice data. Each day started with 3 hours of lectures in the morning followed by 3 hours of hands-on work after lunch.</description></item></channel></rss>